In this example, you're going to learn how to
在这个例子里 你要学会如何
execute code with a continue statement in it.
执行含有continue语句的代码
Here, we have a for loop that has a continue statement inside.
这是一个含有continue语句的for循环
With a for loop, when you execute a continue statement,
当你在for循环中 执行continue命令
the loop increment is performed with the continue.
循环参数增量会和continue语句一起执行
To see this, let us first convert this for loop to the equivalent while loop.
为了理解它 让我们先将for循环转换为相同功能的while循环
Here, we've taken one step in the conversion process,
在这里 我们已经做了转换过程当中的一步
moving the variable declaration before the loop.
将变量声明移动到循环之前
To move this closer to being a while loop,
要将这个更接近while循环
we've moved the increment statement i++ to the end of the loop.
我们将递增命令i++移动到循环结束的地方
But notice that we also put i++ right before the continue statement.
但注意 我们也会将i++放在continue语句之前
Now, we've finished changing this for loop to an equivalent while loop.
现在 我们完成了将for循环转换成while循环
Since i will go out of scope at the end of the function anyways,
由于在功能结束时 我会涉及到超出课程范围的内容
we can get rid of the extra curly braces that we
我们不需要这些额外的大括号
wrote here without changing our code's behavior.
写在这里的 不改变代码的行为
Now we are ready to begin executing.
现在我们可以开始执行代码了
We begin by calling our printRemainders function,
我们从调用printRemainders功能开始
passing in negative two,
初始值为-2
four and five as parameters.
4和5作为参数
We then declare i and initialize it to lo and reach our while loop.
我们定义i 初始值为值（-2） 并开始while循环
i less than high is true,
i小于最高值为真
so we enter the while loop.
所以我们进入while循环
i equals zero is false,
i等于0为假
so we skip past the if statement and print five mod negative two is one.
因此我们跳过if语句 并打印出5除以-2的余数是1
We increment i and now have reached the end of the while loop.
i递增 我们现在到了while循环的结束部分
So, we go back to the top of the loop.
我们回到循环顶端
i less than hi is true,
i小于最高值为真
so we enter the loop body.
所以我们进入循环
Again, i is not zero,
同样的 i不等于0
so we skip the if statement and print out five mod negative one is zero.
我们跳过if语句 并打印出5除以-1余数是0
We increment i and then return to the top of the loop.
i递增 然后回到循环顶端
i less than hi is still true,
i小于最高值为真
so we go inside the loop body.
我们进入循环
However, now i is zero,
i等于0
so we entered the then clause of this if statement.
我们进入if语句的then部分
We print that we cannot divide by zero.
打印出我们无法把0当作除数
Increment i and now reach the continue statement.
i递增 进入continue部分
The continue statement just takes us to the start of the loop again,
continue将我们带到循环的开始
right before we check the loop condition,
在我们检查循环条件之前
so we move the execution arrow back here.
我们将执行箭头挪回这里
Now we just do the next loop iteration as you would expect.
我们现在进行下一个迭代过程
Since i is one not zero,
i是1 不是0
printing out a message and incrementing i.
打印出信息 i递增
We do the loop again with i being two,
我们再次进行循环 此时i等于2
printing out that five mod two is one,
打印出5除以2余数是1
and finally, one more time,
最后 再一次
through the loop with i being three.
i等于3 进入循环
After this last iteration,
经过最后一轮迭代
i less than hi is false,
i小于最高值为假
so we skip the body of the while loop and return from printRemainders.
所以我们跳过while循环 从printRemainders返回
Now, we return from main, exiting the program.
现在 从main函数返回 退出程序